so before we go into how predication
works in hardware let's first look at
the technique called if conversion which
is how the compiler creates the code
that will be executed along both paths
so let's say we have a relatively small
if then else here where depending on the
condition
x gets either the value from array of i
or array from j
and y gets either incremented or
decremented
if conversion transforms this code into
the work of both parts
followed by a selection of some sort
between the results of the two parts
but there is still a question of how do
we do this
if we convert this into some sort of a
conditional expression that still
branches based on the condition and then
does the move of x2 into x otherwise
does the move of x into x1 then we
really haven't done much because we
converted one branch
into another branch and now we have this
branch twice so unless we have some sort
of a correlating predictor like for
example
the global history predictor we will
possibly have two mispredictions here
instead of the one we might have had
so if this is all you can do then you
don't do if conversion what we need for
if conversion to work
is some sort of a move instruction that
will do something like
move x1 into x if
a flag is true